Radio Free Europe/Radio Liberty, Inclusive: 1973-1991, Bulk: 1981-82, 1987-1988
Baylor University, The Keston Center for Religion, Politics, and Society
Radio Free Europe/Radio Liberty
Inclusive: 1973-1991, Bulk: 1981-82, 1987-1988
Baylor University, The Keston Center for Religion, Politics, and Society http://www.baylor.edu/kestoncenter/
12
Keston Institute, 1969 -
7 document boxes
The Radio Free Europe/ Radio Liberty Subject Files contain RFE/RL publications on Poland, Czechoslovakia, Romania, Eastern Europe, the Baltic area, Hungary, China, and Yugoslavia.
Administrative Information
Physical Description
General condition: Good.
Biography/Profile
Keston College, originally founded in 1969 as the Center for the Study of Religion and Communism with the named changed to Keston College in 1974, collected and publicized details about religious persecution behind the Iron Curtain, becoming “the voice of the voiceless.” After the collapse of communism in the 1990s, Keston College moved to Oxford and downsized due to decreased funding. The name eventually changed to Keston Institute. In 2007, the Institute transferred the Keston Archive and Library to the newly created Keston Center for Religion, Politics, and Society at Baylor University.
Keston collected, verified, translated, and disseminated information received from believers in the Soviet Union, Poland, Romania, Czechoslovakia, Hungary, Yugoslavia, Bulgaria and other communist countries. The Keston Archive and Library housed numerous letters, petitions, reports and underground publications (Samizdat) from believers of various denominations along with officially published books and periodicals.
From the early 1970’s through the early 1990’s, Keston collected materials and documents created by and related to Radio Free Europe/Radio Liberty
According to the Radio Free Europe/Radio Liberty website https://www.rferl.org, the news service was founded in 1949 near the beginning of the Cold War to transmit uncensored news and information to audiences behind the Iron Curtain. The United States Congress funds RFE/RL through the Broadcasting Board of Governors, a bipartisan federal agency that oversees all U.S. international broadcasting services.
Radio Free Europe/Radio Liberty provides news, information and analysis in 25 languages to 23 countries in Eastern Europe, Central Asia and the Middle East, serving as one of the world’s most comprehensive news operations in the world. More than 400 full-time journalists report from the front lines, often putting their lives at risk in the fight for media freedom. They report information, host briefings and special events from both Washington, D.C. and Prague in the Czech Republic. The stated “mission of Radio Free Europe/Radio Liberty (RFE/RL) is to promote democratic values and institutions by reporting the news in countries where a free press is banned by the government or not fully established. RFE/RL’s journalists provide what many people cannot get locally: uncensored news, responsible discussion, and open debate.”
Scope and Content
The Radio Free Europe/ Radio Liberty subject files consist of Situation Reports, RAD Background Reports, Articles, BBC/Current Affairs Talks, Independent Press Summaries, Subject Indexes, Press Surveys, and miscellaneous reports.
The materials cover a period from 1968 to 1991 with the bulk from 1981-82 and 1987-88. The most notable topics include Poland, Czechoslovakia, Romania, Eastern Europe, the Baltic area, Hungary, China, and Yugoslavia.
Arrangement
The Keston Center received most of the RFE/LR material organized by specific categories. This original filing system has been preserved as much as possible. The RFE/LR materials received by the Keston Center in no particular order are arranged by country, title, and chronology.
Access Restrictions
All requests for copying of materials must be submitted to the Keston Center for Religion, Politics, and Society in writing. Please use the Request Form for Copying Materials sheet. Unpublished materials authored or otherwise produced by the creator (s) of this collection are in the public domain. There are no restrictions on use. Copyright status for other collection materials is unknown. Transmission or reproduction of materials protected by U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) beyond that allowed by fair use requires the written permission of the copyright owners. Works not in the public domain cannot be commercially exploited without permission of the copyright owners. Responsibility for any use rests exclusively with the user.
Acquisition Information
Accession No. 12.
Related Resources
Related references
“History.” Radio Free Europe/Radio Liberty. Accessed December 11, 2017.
“About Us.” Radio Free Europe/Radio Liberty. Accessed December 11, 2017.
“Mission Statement.” Radio Free Europe/Radio Liberty. Accessed December 11, 2017.
Index Terms
Subjects (Organizations)
Keston College -- Archives.; Keston Institute -- Archives.; Radio Free Europe -- Records and correspondence.; Radio Liberty -- Records and correspondence.; RFE/RL -- Records and correspondence.
Subjects
International broadcasting.; News radio stations -- Records and correspondence.
- Poland, 1977-1990; 1
  Administrative Information
  Physical Description
  General condition: Good.
  Biography/Profile
  The Poland series contains Situation Reports, RAD Background Reports, BBC Current Affairs Talk and Research Info., Polish Independent Press Summary, and miscellaneous articles.
  - Situation Report, 1977-1979 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Situation Report, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Situation Report, 1981 January-June (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Situation Report, 1981 July-November (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Situation Report, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Situation Report, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Situation Report, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Situation Report, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - RAD Background Report, 1977, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - RAD Background Report, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - RAD Background Report, 1981 January-March (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - RAD Background Report, 1981 April, July (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - RAD Background Report, 1981 August (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - RAD Background Report, 1981 September-December (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - RAD Background Report, 1982 January-February (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - RAD Background Report, 1982 March, October (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - RAD Background Report, 1983 March-July (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - RAD Background Report, 1984 August- September; 1985 April, December; 1986 September (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - RAD Background Report, 1987 April, December 1988 January (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Articles, 1980, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - BBC/Current Affairs Talks, 1980 February, December; 1982 January-April (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - BBC/Current Affairs Research & Information Section, 1981 January, September-November; 1983 March, October (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - CSCE Digest/Commission on Security & Cooperation in Europe, 1981 December (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Polish Independent Press Summary, 1989-1990 December-January (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Subject Index, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - East Europe Research and Analysis, Polish Press Summary, 1987 August-September (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - East Europe Research and Analysis, Polish Press Summary, 1989 December 5-8,1 1 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - East Europe Research and Analysis, Polish Press Summary, 1989 December 13-15, 19, 29 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - East Europe Research and Analysis, Polish Press Summary, 1990 January 9, 10, 15, 17, 18 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - East Europe Research and Analysis, Polish Press Summary, 1990 January 19, 23, 29, 31, February 1 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - RFE/Research — Polish Press (Folder 31)
  - Review, October 1986, January 1987, March 1988 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous articles, 1981 July 24, 1984 October 30, November 2 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Czechoslovakia, 1974-1989; 2
  The Czechoslovakia series contains Situation Reports, RAD Background Reports, Press Surveys, Subject Indexes and Miscellaneous Reports.
  - Situation Report, 1969 January, April-July, December; 1971 January-February (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Situation Report, 1974 September-December (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Situation Report, 1975 January, April-September (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Situation Report, 1979 February March, May, August; 1980 February, July, November-December; 1981 January, May, October), 1982 January, May, September- December (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Situation Report, 1983 January, March, May, June-October; 1984 February-March, May, July, September; 1985 February-May, September (Folder 5)
  - November, 4; 5 (Folder 6)
  - Situation Report, 1986 March, May-June, September, 1987 June, August, October-December (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Situation Report, 1988 January-March, June- July, December 1989 April-May, July-August (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - RAD Background Report, 1976 March-April, June-July (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - RAD Background Report, 1979 January, April, June, September, 1980 July-August, October-December; 1981 March-April, June-July (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - RAD Background Report, 1982 March, May, September, November-December (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - RAD Background Report, 1983 June, August, December (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - RAD Background Report, 1984 January, March, June, 1989 May (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Press Survey, 1968 November; 1969 March- April; 1970 May, September, December; 1971 March, July, September; 1973 March, 1974 December, 1975 January, March (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Subject Index, 1986-1987 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous reports, 1968 August, September; 1969 March, June, 1984 April (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Romania, 1984-1986; 3
  The Romania series contains Situation Reports and Subject Indexes.
  - Situation Report, 1984 January- April (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Situation Report, 1984 May-July, September (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Situation Report, 1984 October-December (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Situation Report, 1986 January-April (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Situation Report, 1986 May, July-September (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Situation Report, 1986 October-December (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Subject Index, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Eastern Europe, 1987-1989; 4
  The Eastern Europe series contains Weekly Records of Events in Eastern Europe.
  - Weekly Record of Events in Eastern Europe, 1987 July 10-August 28 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Weekly Record of Events in Eastern Europe, 1987 September 11-October 30 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Weekly Record of Events in Eastern Europe, 1987 November 6- December 18 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Weekly Record of Events in Eastern Europe, 1988 January-February (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Weekly Record of Events in Eastern Europe, 1988 March, April (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Weekly Record of Events in Eastern Europe, 1988 May, June (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Weekly Record of Events in Eastern Europe, 1988 July, August (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Weekly Record of Events in Eastern Europe, 1988 September, October (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Weekly Record of Events in Eastern Europe, 1988 November, December (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Weekly Record of Events in Eastern Europe, 1989 January (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Other Areas (Albania, Baltic, China, Eastern Europe, Hungary, Yugoslavia), 1973-1988; 5
  The Other Areas series contains RAD Background Reports, Situation Reports, Foreign Relations, Party Relations, and Subject Indexes.
  - RAD Background Report, 1987 May (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Situation Report, 1984 December, 1985 March, September-October, December (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Situation Report, 1986 March, May, September, December, 1987 August, December (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Situation Report, 1988 March, May-July (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Situation Report, 1988 August-September); 1989 May, July- August (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Situation Report - Hungary, 1974 November (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Foreign Relations - China, 1974 November (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Party Relations - Yugoslavia, 1974 November (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Subject Index, 1973 January-December (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Miscellaneous Reports —Albania, East Europe, and Yugoslavia, 1968 November, 1969 January, March (Box 6, Folder 14)
- Soviet Union, 1968, 1985-1991; 6
  The Soviet Union series contains Soviet Area Audience & Opinion Research, Monthly Index of Background Reports, and Situations Reports, Subject Indexes.
  - Soviet Area Audience & Opinion Research, 1985, 1986 October-December (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Soviet Area Audience & Opinion Research, 1987 April- August, October (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Soviet Area Audience & Opinion Research, 1988 March, December 1989 January- February (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Soviet Area Audience & Opinion Research, 1989 March-August (Folder 4)
  - Soviet Area Audience & Opinion Research, 1989 September-December (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Soviet Area Audience & Opinion Research, 1990 February-March, June, October-December; 1991 January (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Monthly Index of Background Reports and Situation Reports, 1974 August, November (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Subject Index, 1974 January- December (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Subject Index, 1975 January, March-May (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Soviet Union - Miscellaneous, 1968-1970, 1982, 1984-1987 (Box 7, Folder 10)